A Guide to the The Records of the Library in the University Archives Virginia Union University 1927-1996
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
The Records of the Library in the University Archives Virginia Union University 1927-1996
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
AR-001
about 45 files
Virginia Union University Library
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Originally housed in the basement of Coburn Hall, the library was relocated into the Belgian Friendship Building in 1950 and named the William J. Clark Library after the university's third president. In January 1997 the collection moved into the L. Douglas Wilder Library and Learning Resource Center, referred to as the Wilder Library, named in honor of the VUU alumnus, the first elected African American Governor in the United States.
The head librarians have been as follows: Wallace Van Jackson 1927-1941
William A. Griffey 1941-1942
Ann Goode(acting) 1942-1944
Bertha W. Gibbs (acting) 1944- 1946
Verdelle V. Bradley 1946- 1985
Sylvia Jenkins (acting) 1985-1986
Wanda Crenshaw 1986-1989
Dr. Vonita Foster 1989-
Scope and Content Information
These records reflect the growth and development of the Library at Virginia Union University. The bulk of the collection is the annual reports for which there is a virtually complete run from 1927 through 1992, including semi-annual reports and quarterly reports. The Administrative file contains papers created in the day-to-day business such as limited correspondence, floor plans and library objectives and statistics. The Events file contains announcements for library sponsored events such as guest speakers. The Southern Association of Colleges and Schools is an accreditation committee on which Mrs. Bradley served.
The James Weldon Johnson Tribute files relate to a display in the library presented in conjunction with the 1972 Fine Arts Festival (AR-0004) tribute to Johnson. The correspondence is between Ms. O.J. Okala, nurse to Johnson's widow, and Mrs. Bradley. The display materials are mainly biographical sketches and sheet music (the newspaper clippings have been moved to the Clippings File under Johnson, James Weldon).
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically and chronological therein.
Contents List
- Administrative (Box 1)
- Annual Reports 1927-1928, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
- Annual Reports 1940-1995 (Box 1)
- Bibliographies (Box 1)
- Circulation Statistics Record (Box 1)
- Events (Box 1)
- James Weldon Johnson Tribute-Correspondence (Box 1)
- James Weldon Johnson Tribute-Display Materials (Box 1)
- James Weldon Johnson Tribute-Photographs (Box 1)
- L. Douglas Wilder Lecture Series 1997 (Box 1)
- L. Douglas Wilder Lecture Series, photographs (Box 1)
- Library Bulletin (Box 1)
- Lost Books 1960-1966 (Box 1)
- Neighborhood Youth Corps 1968-1969, 1971 (Box 1)
- Newsletter 1997 (Box 1)
- Photographs (Box 1)
- Sound Recording Lists (Box 1)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (Box 1)
- Student Assistants 1966-1976 (Box 1)
- The Tower(newsletter) 1990-1996 (Box 1)